<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Ziegler&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>http://samziegler.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sam Ziegler&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://samziegler.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Merkle trees</title>
      <link>http://samziegler.me/posts/merkle-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samziegler.me/posts/merkle-trees/</guid>
      <description>Merkle Trees and MAST    Merkelized Abstract Syntax Trees (MAST) is a scheme for pay-to-script-hash outputs which critically improves the privacy and smart contract capabilities of Bitcoin. The locking script of a UTXO can be a complicated contract, with many possible ways of being spent. MAST ensures that the only part of the script that makes it into the blockchain is the part which is actually satisfied by a spender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taproot: what is it and what does it mean for Bitcoin?</title>
      <link>http://samziegler.me/posts/taproot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samziegler.me/posts/taproot/</guid>
      <description>In November 2021, at block height 709,632, the Taproot upgrade became active on the Bitcoin network, meaning this block was the first for which Bitcoin nodes started enforcing the updated consensus rules. But what is Taproot, and how did it come to be adopted on the network?
There are really several innovations bundled under the umbrella of “Taproot.” These include:
 Schnorr signatures (BIP-340) Taproot outputs (BIP-341) Tapscript (BIP-342)  I won&amp;rsquo;t attempt to describe all of these in one post, so for now we will focus on the first of these: a new cryptographic signature scheme for Bitcoin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some learnings about Bitcoin</title>
      <link>http://samziegler.me/posts/some-learnings-about-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samziegler.me/posts/some-learnings-about-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, I attended a talk given by Andreas Antonopolous at a Bitcoin meetup in downtown San Francisco. Coming into the talk, I had thought very little about Bitcoin, or &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; technology more generally. The way that Andreas spoke about Bitcoin and the economic, social, and technical implications that it has for our world was nothing short of inspiring. I emerged with a profound curiosity for this new monetary technology and what it might mean about the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://samziegler.me/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://samziegler.me/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I hope to share my thoughts on programming, music, math, bitcoin, cryptography, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
